This is baby Manda. She had no idea that
one day she would grow up and a man she
cared for would punch her in the face.
This is four-year-old Manda. She had no
idea that one day she'd grow up and a
man she loved would choke slam her. This
is 8-year-old Amanda who would one day
consume a lot of liquor and then get
taken advantage of. This is 12-year-old
Amanda who didn't know that one day
she'd be mushed by a man she cared
about. This is 16-year-old Amanda, who
didn't know that one day she'd be stolen
from by several men she cared about.
This is 26-year-old Amanda, who didn't
know that one day she'd be having a
miscarriage and her partner would leave
her at the hospital. This is 39-year-old
Amanda, who didn't know that someday
soon she would be sexually assaulted in
a hotel room while her partner lay
asleep in the bed next to her.
And this is 44year-old Amanda who
understands that there is no dollar
amount
that would cure any of that trauma. Who
understands that when we seek justice
and accountability, it does not equate
to healing.
money, jail sentences are all simply
deterrence that society has come up with
to try to quell the abuse from
continuing. While it continues to
perpetuate the falsehood that women are
objects and lesser than, all of us were
once young people in a world that has
been waiting for us and we are trying to
find our way through. And in that
process, we face those who harm us. And
we try our best to get to the other
side,
knowing that no matter how much money
abusers are forced to pay or how much
jail time they are forced to serve, it
does not make them less likely to abuse.
And it does not heal them from what
caused them to become abusers in the
first place. It does not change that we
are tasked with working on not how to
get over, but how to get through.
Because no matter what they tell you,
this life is long. And even with all the
abuse that I've suffered, and so many of
us have suffered, I carry no bitterness
towards men. I carry a purpose to make a
world that does not create men who think
like this.